Contact

aryaman010@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/aryaman-bhardwaj-20876918b (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

SolidWorks

ANSYS

Automotive Design

Languages

English (Professional Working)
Hindi (Full Professional)

Certifications

Thermodynamics
Mechanics of Materials I
Strategy Consulting
Certified Solidworks Associate
(CSWA)

Machine Learning with Python

Honors-Awards
BAJA SAE Louisville 2020

Aryaman Bhardwaj

Mechanical Engineer | Automation | BAJA SAE Delhi

Summary

With a diverse experience in structural engineering, machine designing and have a brief knowledge in Finite Element Analysis. Skilled in Automotive Engineering, SolidWorks, Fusion 360, 3D Design and ANSYS. Strong automotive undergrad with a Bachelor's degree focused on Mechanical Engineering from Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore.

Experience

Team Jaabaz - Baja SAE VIT Transmission Engineer January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months) Vellore Area, India

Our team has made India's first 4WD ATV ever to participate in an BAJA SAE International Event. I am working under the Transmission Department of the team. Team Jaabaz is the Official BAJA SAE Team of Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore. The team builds their own ATV and participates in BAJA International in USA every year.

Worked with the team for the international event of BAJA SAE LOUISVILLE-Rank 4 Overall, Rank 6 in Design out of 100 teams worldwide, also 1st position in Asia.

Distinct Horizon
Research And Development Engineer
June 2020 - Present (3 months)
Delhi, India

Working on designing agricultural machines for better farming productivity with the use of less chemicals resulting in profits to the farmers and betterment of Mother Earth.

F.E.P.S.I Human Resource January 2019 - Present (1 year 8 months) F.E.P.S.I is a youth run non-profit organization which covers different projects for the betterment of the environment.

Boston Consulting Group (BCG) Strategic Consultant May 2020 - May 2020 (1 month)

I did a virtual internship with BCG due to the COVID-19 crisis. I worked as a strategy consultant for the same and was tasked to come up with marketing and sales ideas for a cellular network company which was facing losses from past 2 years.

The most successful solution we worked upon was how handset leasing can help boost up sales and profit. Devising the steps we need to take in order to implement this plan in a phased manner, costing and explanation to shareholders was also handled by me during this internship.

graVITas VIT
Event Coordinator
October 2019 - October 2019 (1 month)

Managed the events in Gravitas, Technical Fest conducted by Vellore Institute of Technology, Vellore.

Education

Vellore Institute of Technology
Bachelor's degree, Mechanical Engineering · (2018 - 2022)

Ahlcon Public School High School Diploma, Non-Med · (2016 - 2018)